Nivapa has again launched a new plan
for 2024, its latest plan was
Aspire, now the latest plan for 2025 is
Niva Buppsur 3.0, Indian customers are very
excited.  The agents are also very
excited.  The customer care people
are more excited to sell because
here you get the option of unlimited cover.
You heard it right.
Whatever it was, 10 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 30 lakh,
it has now become old.  Directly the company has
given you the option of unlimited cover.
That means tomorrow if you incur expenses of Rs 50 lakh, Rs 1
crore, Rs 2 crore or even Rs 10 crore
in your hospital, the company will pay you.
But there are many limitations in this plan
which you need to understand.
And if after listening to the words of the Else company, you also
say unlimited, then you will get trapped.  If
you talk to any agent or customer, they will
show you in such a way that there is no
other plan in the market except this plan
and no plan with more value for
money than this is being sold in the market.
But you don't have to listen to them.
Because after watching this video your
entire perception is going to change.  Because
in this video I will explain to you in detail every single thing, every single
condition, how every single feature works.
So that you can take an informed decision.
So without wasting time let's get
started.  The same Ashor 3.0 plan
comes in four different variants.  Classic,
Select Elite and Black.  Whichever of these four plans
you buy, you will
get the option of unlimited cover.  But in all these four
plans you get to see capping of room rent.
Like in Classic,
you get to see the capping of General category of rooms.
That means you can get admitted only in the general rooms.  If you
go to a room with a bed, you will have to pay from your pocket.
However, if you opt for the Select plan,
you will be limited to twin sharing.
For the Elite plan, you are
given a single private AC room with attached
bathroom.  That means you cannot access Telks and Suites
and you do
not see any room rent limit in Black.
That means the company wants you guys to
take the black plan.  So that you
get the option of no room rent limit.  That means the company will somehow
force you to go for the black option.
You can see similar limits
for modern treatments also.
Classic and Select customers have been given a limit of ₹1 lakh.
That too for a complete claim.  That means
you cannot claim more than Rs 1 lakh for all three – pre, post and hospitalization.   At the same time,
if I talk about Alt and Black ones, then no
kind of limit has been
given here.  That means up to some in
short, modern treatment is covered for both black
and white people.  The
company has given an add-on option for Classic and Select customers.  In
which, if you
pay extra premium, then this
limit of air ambulance or road
ambulance or modern treatment gets
removed.  Next thing is the Lock the Clock
feature.  You can see this only in Elite and Black
plans.  The
premium of health insurance
depends on your age.  That means the older I am,
the higher
my premium will be.  That means if the premium for an 18
year old person is Rs 10,000 then the
premium for a 60 year old person can be Rs 4,500.
Because a person above 60 years of age has a
higher risk of falling ill.  According to this, the
company has kept different premiums for every age.  The
company has kept it like this.  But
apart from this, a lock the clock feature was also provided.
That means the company says that until you make a
claim in this plan, we will
charge your premium as per the entry age.  Now what is this entry age
?  Entry age is the age at which
you first buy the policy.   Do
n't get confused after seeing this thing.  This is the
first time I have taken a policy in 28 years.  NVP
3.0 10,000 is my premium.  Here, when it will be
only Rs 10,000 in 60 years, there will be plus
inflation.  So, this inflation is the reason
I will not understand how much the company is
charging me.  It will be affordable for two-three years
but may not be affordable even after that.
Or I'll get
caught up in a plan that's
just stuck here because of the lock the clock.
And
Twice Thrice is 10 times better than the latest plans that came in the market.
For example, those who had
taken Rio three-four years
ago because of Lock the Clock, they got trapped because there was no
option of unlimited there.
You have got the lollipop of unlimited
in this plan.  In 3.0,
you will be stuck with the same plan due to Lock the Clock.
Think that my premium is locked in for 10-20 years.  Will
you continue till 60 or will you
continue till retirement?  But you will lag
far behind in the market.  And as soon as
you claim till 61, 62, 65, the
premium will increase so much that you will
not be able to afford it at your retirement.  So this
is the perspective because I am afraid that
if you are fit and fine then
you should upgrade the plan in 4 to 5 years.
Because any company gives you a plan in the market
and you
also get continuity benefits.  If you are a 4 year
old customer then you will be considered as a 4 year old customer only.
This is my perspective.  Yours may be
different too.  But that's why I feel
bad.  Next is
expenses during hospitalization
including AYUSH.  Covered up to some in short
for all hospitalizations.  All hospitalizations that last more than 2 hours
are covered.  Except AYUSH, AYUSH
treatment requires at least 24 plus hours
of hospitalization.  When
you are admitted to the hospital,
you are given some extra things according to your room.
Like you are given food
according to your diet or you are
given a TV or some extra sleepers, all those things.  But if
apart from all those things you are taking extra things which are
not linked to your treatment.   For example, if
you have some extra food
or some beverage or toiletries or
you have ordered some cosmetic item
in the hospital, then the
companies will not pay for all those things, the biggest thing is that
only the monofocal lens of Classic and Select variants will be covered for cataract operation, there is
no such limitation for Alt and Black variants.
If you are undergoing MRI CT scan,
endoscopy, colonoscopy or any other
diagnostic procedure and
you are admitted for that purpose and no
active line of treatment is going on.
That means you are just being investigated to find out what
happened to you, so you will not get any money for that thing.
No matter how much unlimited cover you have.
You get to see different room rent limits in all four variants of 3.0.
But if you
move into a room beyond your room rent limit, you will have to pay a comment
which is clearly mentioned here.
Here is the complete co-payment list.
If you are eligible for a general room and
switch to twin sharing, you will have to pay a
co-payment of 20%.  Here it is.  And if
you have an elite plan and you go to a
deluxe or suite room,
you will still have to pay a co-payment of 20%.  If you do
not want to be charged any co-payment, then go to the room
for which you are eligible and get ready to
pay this co-payment.
Next is expenses before and after
hospitalization which is covered for 60 and 180 days.
Up to some in and shot.
Before going to the hospital, whatever your
X-ray, sonography, doctor's fees or
any local doctor you went to for such
tests,
if you have the bill, prescriptions,
list of all those medicines, then
you can claim all those things on reimbursement
basis in this plan
and as soon as you get discharged from the hospital,
for recovery also, the doctor has
prescribed pills that you have to
eat all these things, you have to get all these tests done, you have to
take physiotherapy, you have to take this, you have to take that, you have to get
follow up with the doctor, all those
things will also be covered for up to 180 days
but it is necessary for you to have the bill, prescription of each and every
thing.  You will
get that also in reimbursement.  Next is home
care treatment and domiciliary treatment.
It is covered up to sum and short.  There are
some terms and conditions without any limitations
which you need to understand.  First of all,
doctor's
advice is necessary to take home care treatment.  It is important to have a second active line of
treatment.
Even in home care treatment, you will
get full reimbursement for pre and post hospitalization.   The
restrictions are that the machines used in
your home like pulse machine,
oximeter, blood pressure machine or sugar
monitoring machine or automation devices
like peritoneal dialysis machine, SHIP and
BIP, clutches, wheelchairs and many more
things.  All those things will
not be covered and you will have to pay for them from your pocket.
Next is organ donor.
You get to see coverage up to sum and shot.
But if you look at the terms and conditions,
many of them are mentioned here.
For example, if you are
undergoing a transplant and you have a policy, then
you are going to get an organ from someone else or from
your family, then suppose the
member who is donating to you does
not have insurance.  But
still, your insurance will
cover all the expenses incurred in extracting or harvesting the organ.  In the terms and conditions, the
company has clearly mentioned that the
company will give you the harvesting cost.
You are an insured person and if you yourself
want to donate your organ to someone else, then the
harvesting cost and the
cost of removing it from you, all these
things are also covered which are clearly
mentioned here.  Many policies do
not cover the harvesting cost itself.
If you yourself want to donate an organ to someone.
Next is Leave Healthy
Discount.  This is one of my favorites.  Because
here you get renewal discount up to 30%.
Now what is this thing?
Here you have to run and walk.
So
you will be given discount according to the number of steps you take.  Here is its chart.
You can understand it yourself by looking at it.
You will see this in your respective Nivpa application.
As soon as you take the policy,
you have to download the NVOP application
and the Google FIT application
if you are using an Android phone
and the Health application
if you are using an iPhone.
This tracking app calculates your steps
and
syncs with the Niva UPA application in the background.  According to that
you get points and you will get discount according to the
number of steps you have taken throughout the year.
Next is day one pre existing disease
loading.  Now, whatever health
conditions or pre-existing diseases you have
before taking the insurance, all those things will be
covered from day one.
Whether it is one, two, three or any number from these lists,
if the company accepts it, you will get
cover from day one.  The only condition is that
you will have to pay extra loading which is
clearly mentioned here.  For example,
if I have blood pressure, diabetes
and let's say cholesterol also.  These three
diseases occurred.  Before I take insurance,
if the company imposes 15% loading on it,
15% and 15%, then I will have to pay 45%
extra premium.
If I am taking an individual policy only on my premium
and suppose if it is a
floater policy that means wife, husband
and children are also included then
loading will be applicable only on the premium of the person who has the health condition.  The
company has provided 145 diseases.
This doesn't mean
you'll be covered if everything happens.  The company will
not accept such proposals.  There are two or four or
if the company feels that the risk may reduce
in the future then it will easily
accept you, just get ready to give uploading.
Here is part two.  You guys
can go and watch it in continuation and if you
liked the video then please like it because
if you like it then it
goes in the recommendations to others also.  People
like it but they don't like it.
So please like it.  And thank you for watching this
video guys.  Have a goodbye.